<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Silent Developer</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 22:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 22:54:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Concept Workflows</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When working through the concept of the “Gamebook Adventures”, I spent some time figuring out how I wanted to deploy my first app (and hopefully others to follow). At first I really wanted to work with native iOS and Swift as the language is quite enjoyable to use and modern. However, despite these advantages I didn’t want to be locked into the Apple ecosystem, and I’m not quite ready to build an independent framework to use on Android devices. I wound up choosing &lt;a href=&quot;https://unity.com&quot;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt; as the engine due to accessibility and relative ease of use. One of the assets I am fond of, and using in my projects is &lt;a href=&quot;https://fungusgames.com/&quot;&gt;Fungus&lt;/a&gt;. Although I have built a great deal of independent logic outside of this asset, it is a great tool to automate and visualize flow of the novel. It also excels when there is a need to generate repetitive tasks. Hopefully as I become nearer to completion, there isn’t any unintended side effect of a large, robust workflow. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/flowchart.png&quot; alt=&quot;Flowchart&quot; /&gt;
A small excerpt of the story with a battle sequence can be viewed here. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N3aVcsbydmc&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/concept-workflows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/09/19/concept-workflows/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tome of Malice&amp;#58 Skills, Stats and Inventories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The series of “Game Book Adventures” I am trying to create are similar to the
classical Fighting Fantasy Adventures of the early 80’s, but with their own unique flair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main stat which is similar to a “Score” in the early adventure games is called Fame. Similar
to the attribute from the Ultima Online game, this can go up and down through your adventure based
on the actions you take. Will you finish the adventure and be Nameless or Glorious?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two random attributes rolled at the beginning of the adventure when you choose your Avatar.
They are Strength and Luck. There are numerous feats through the journey which require a saving roll against these two attributes. A third attribute is your Stamina which at this time will be a static value for all players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strength: Random value between 6-12. Used for feats requiring brute force&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck: Random value between 6-12. Used for feats requiring chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stamina: Value which determines your health points. When this value reaches zero, it’s game over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be two groups of inventories. The core inventory panel manages items discovered on your journey which can affect your choices through the story. Other pickups include healing potions which restore your health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second type of inventory is the weapon panel on the main HUD. There are five slots and at least five possible weapons to obtain through the story. If more are included, no story path should receive more than five. Some weapons will have a number of charges before being destroyed. Damage is independent of your strengh attribute which is only tested through feat encounters via the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some very preliminary walkthrough of the prologue can be viewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v3zyC0sO4Bw&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/14/tome-of-malice-concept/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/09/14/tome-of-malice-concept/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
